# Brian Mwendwa

Nairobi, Kenya



brianmwendwa.mu@gmail.com



+254796898480



linkedin.com/in/brian-mwendwa-25326a173

# Summary

I am naturally inquisitive; I like to learn and explore new ideas. I believe in the inevitability of change and work towards adapting to change. I am a passionate software developer with experience in JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Cloud Development and Architecture. The fable of the Crow and the Pitcher is what best represents my professional journey.

## **Experience**



#### Software Developer

#### pemtergroup

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021 (7 months)

- 1. Collaborated with a team of developers and designers to create a web application in ReactJS.
- 2. Designed the data and presentation layer of the web application's front-end.
- 3. Used additional JavaScript libraries such as React Context API to manage the web application's state, derive computed data from the state of the system, and make asynchronous API calls in JavaScript.
- 4. Translated the client's technical requirements into code.
- 5. Tested and updated the web application so that it can be used on all web browsers.

### **Junior Web Developer**

#### Conceptshub

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021 (3 months)

- 1. Assisted the web development team with all aspects of website and application design with Figma and Material-UI.
- 2. Assisted with the testing and maintenance of backend and front-end applications with Express, Mongo and React JS
- 3. Brainstormed new tech applications such as digital storage and mobile technology.
- 4. Collaborated with developers to implement new web features.



#### Web Developer

#### vulnerablechildrenconcernskenya

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021 (5 months)

- 1. Wrote well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices
- 2. Built website layout/user interfaces by using standard HTML/CSS practices Integrating data from various back-end services and databases.



## Information Technology Intern

Kenya Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock, Fisheries and Cooperatives

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019 (4 months)

- 1. Handled network routing and configuration for various departments within the Ministry.
- 2. Installed and configured computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers, and scanners.
- 3. Provided technical support across the company.

#### **Education**



Bachelor's degree, IT 2018 - 2021

# KCA University

CCNA, System, Networking, and LAN/WAN Management/Manager 2019 - 2020

# Starehe Boys' Centre and School

High School Diploma Jan 2013 - Nov 2017

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

Blockchain Intro - IBM gs180234bsit@aiu.ac.ke

# SOLOLEARN HTML FUNDAMENTALS CERTIFICATE - Sololearn

Certificate #1014-9733611

Usable Security - Coursera
3UTB6ZM8RZKV

# Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA) - Cisco

- API IBM
- Node.js V2 IBM
- (A) JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures freeCodeCamp
- Modern JavaScript for ReactJS ES6 Udemy UC-1ad2b96d-feef-45a1-bd8c-19f98d0a967b

# AWS Services for Solutions Architect 2021 - Udemy

UC-6947d87c-dca5-4d93-8dbd-1d2f959a00b1

# **Skills**

Programming • React.js • MongoDB • JavaScript • Web Development

# **Honors & Awards**

# **Certificate of Participation** - Kenya Red Cross Youth

Aug 2016

Was enrolled as a Youth Member of the Kenya Red Cross Society, joining others all over the world to help the sick and suffering.